--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:轻轻  字幕来源:网络  调校:Dulupone  招募Q号:76846146
主演: 尤·伯连纳
索太罗 我的好朋友
Sotero! My good friend.
你好吗？
How are ya?
有没有什么喝的东西？
You have a drink?
看到这样的村庄真是高兴
I can't tell you what a pleasure it is to see a village like this.
安诺斯
Santos!
外面的的世界有太多的不安和转变
So much restlessness and change in the outside world.
人们已变得不容易满足
People no longer content with their station in life.
妇女的服装… 不知羞耻
Women's fashions? Shameless.
雪茄
Cigar.
这里有宗教
Mire! Religion!
看到宗教已成过去式时 你真的会想哭
You'd weep if you saw how true religion is now a thing of the past.
上个月 我们在圣祖安 那是个富有的城市 坐下
Last month we were in San Juan...a rich town. Sit down.
被神眷顾的富有城市
Rich town, much blessed by God.
大教堂
Big church.
不像这里的小教堂 神父一年才来两次 是大的
Not like here...little church, priest comes twice a year. Big one!
你可以想象我们找到金烛台和满溢的捐款箱
You think we find gold candlesticks, poor box filled to overflowing?
你知道我们找到了什么？
You know what we found?
铜烛台和近乎全空的捐款箱
Brass candlesticks, almost nothing in the poor box.
但我们还是拿走了
But we took it anyway.
我知道我们还是拿走了
I know we took it anyway.
我只是想告诉他现代人信仰不深
I'm trying to show him how little religion some people now have.
这我现在就可以领会
That I could see for myself.
不要领会
Don't see!
你若有我这种责任时 会怎么做？
What if you had to carry my load, huh?
供应食物 像慈父喂婴儿
The need to provide food, like a father, to fill the mouths of his hungry men.
枪枝 武器
Guns. Ammunition.
你知道那要多少钱吗？
You know how much money that costs? Huh? Huh?!
不知道
No.
打猎的好日子结束了
The days of good hunting are over.
曾经有马 牛 金子 树上的水果 不再有了
Once there was horses, cattle, gold, fruit from the trees. No more.
现在我狩猎 头上是赏金 脚后是骑警
Now I must hunt with a price on my head, rurales at my heels.
我会再回来的
I'll be back.
够了
Enough!
剩下的等回来时再拿
We'll get the rest when we come back.
我爱这个村庄
I love this village.
我也知道你们有你们的困难…
I know you have your problems...
杀人犯 盗贼
Murderer! Thief!
路易
Rafael!
Rafael...
路易
Rafael!
笨蛋
Stupid!
我们应该很快会有另一次讨论
We have to have another discussion very soon.
我很高兴常听到我的朋友索太罗的看法
It's always a pleasure to hear the views of my good friend Sotero.
也许当我回来时吧
Maybe when I come back, hm?
再见
Adiós!
咱们走
Let's go!
帮我把他带进去
Help me bring him in.
如果他再抢走我们的收成…
If he steals our harvest again,...
我们干脆死了 那还痛快些
..we might as well cut our throats and be done with it!
离开这条村 我们必须这样做
Leave the valley. That's what we must do.
在另一个地方生活？
Live somewhere else?
把家搬走？我们的田地也弄走？
Take our homes with us? Our farms?
我们… 可以偷偷藏起一些食物
We... could hide some food.
不让卡贝拉知道？他从不拿走全部食物
From Calvera? He never steals all our food.
每次都会留下一些让我们活下去
He leaves us enough to go on with.
好伟大啊
That's something.
我们可以求他多留一点食物
We could beg him to leave us more.
不 不 那会使他更生气 我不认为我们该有什么行动
No, no. That would make him more angry. I don't think we should do anything.
我们一定得采取些行动
We must do something!
想象路易一样？说话理性点
Like Rafael? Talk sense.
我们在田间努力工作 肚子却空空如也
We break our backs in the fields, and our bellies stay empty.
我们一定得想个办法
We must do something!
We must do something.
什么办法？
But what?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我们去问那位长者
We'll ask the old man.
他会知道的
He'll know.
战斗
Fight.
你们一定得战斗 战斗
You must fight. Fight!
用弯刀和赤手空拳对付枪？
With machetes and bare hands against guns?!
买枪
Buy guns.
买枪？
Buy?
去边界 那边有很多枪
Go to the border. Guns are plentiful there.
但我们用什么钱买？
But what are we going to use for money?
把这卖掉
Sell that.
和其他任何可卖的东西
And anything else you can collect.
即使有了枪…
Even if we had the guns,...
我们只知道种田 不知道怎么用枪杀人
..we know how to plant and grow, we don't know how to kill.
去学啊
Then learn.
不然就等死
Or die.
嘿 我正在等你们
Hey! I've been waitin' for you.
你的事办的不错呀
Oh, you did a wonderful job.
对不起 朋友 不能举殡了
I'm sorry, but there'll be no funeral.
什么？
What?!
墓已掘好 殓葬师已为他整理好…
The grave's dug, and the defunct is as ready as the embalmer can make him...
但不能举殡
..but there'll be no funeral.
怎么了 是我钱付的不够吗？
Didn't I pay you enough?
这不是钱的问题 为这二十元 我肯理葬任何人
It's not a question of money. For $20, I'd plant anybody with a whoop and a holler.
不过葬礼已经完了
But the funeral's off.
你怎么会这样的？
Well, how d'ya like that?!
我想葬他 你也想 如果他能坐起来说话 也会赞成
I want him buried. You want him buried. If he could sit up and talk, he'd second the motion.
没有人会有异议的
That's as unanimous as you can get.
朋友 你做了件好事 但你…
You've behaved like a brother and a Christian, but you...
我不想听什么赞美的话
Now, look. I'm not lookin' for any praise.
我是个流动小贩… 卖女人内衣
I'm a travelling salesman...ladies' corsets.
走在街上 有个人在我面前死掉
I'm walking down the street and a man drops dead.
两小时内人们继续步伐不停 没有人帮忙
For two hours people stepped over him, without lifting a finger.
我只是做了我该做的
I'm doing what any decent man would.
亨瑞 我们走吧…
Come on, Henry, let's get on stage...
不 等一下 这个人得下葬
No! Wait a minute. This man has to be buried.
不久后他不会变成香花(发臭)
And soon he's not turning into a nosegay.
我知道 如果可以的话我会做的 但…
I know. I would if I could, but...
但是城内有反对份子
..there's an element in town that objects.
反对？反对什么？
Objects? To what?
他们说他不配埋在那里
They say he isn't fit to be buried there.
什么？在根山？
What? In Boot Hill?
那边埋的都是杀人犯 自杀的和被遗弃的老酒鬼
There's nothing there but murderers, cutthroats and derelict old barflies.
他们也会同意的
And if they ever felt exclusive, they're past it now.
但他们是白人 朋友
They happen to be white, friend.
而老山姆…
And old Sam...
老山姆却是个印地安人
Well, old Sam was an Indian.
真他妈的
Well, I'll be damned!
我想不到将尸体运进根山你们还有问题
I never knew you had to be anything but a corpse to get into Boot Hill.
这到底有多久了？
How long's this been going on?
自从我们开始"文明化"后
Since the town got civilized.
这不是我弄的 我也不高兴这样
It's not my doin', boys. I don't like it. No, sir.
我总是对所有人都一样 就当他们是我的潜在客户一般
I've always treated every man the same just as another future customer.
既然如此 驶动那辆灵柩车吧
In that case, get that hearse rollin'.
不行啊 驾车的人也跑了
My carriage driver's quit.
他也会得到好处的
He's prejudiced too, huh?
他不会干的 因为他的头有可能被打爆
If it comes to gettin' his head blown off.
那找别人
Well, get somebody else.
没有人肯驾这车 所以还你
Nobody else will drive it! So here.
拿着 如果就这么点事 我来驾这车
Oh, hell! If that's all that's holding things up, I'll drive the rig.
你那散弹枪能不能借我用？
Can I borrow that scatter-gun?
当然可以
You're more than welcome.
嘿 你等一下 这辆车在丹佛买的花了我八百四十元
Hey! Wait a minute there. This hearse cost me $840.
全区只有这么一辆
It's the only one in the county.
我不会允许让陌生人驾驶这车去让子弹打成碎片
I'll be darned if I let it be shot at.
任何损伤由我来付
I'll pay for the damages.
这我到要看看
I wanna see this.
我也要
Me, too!
我从没在灵车上拿枪坐过
Never rode shotgun on a hearse before.
走吧
Let her buck.
你是新来的吗？
New in town?
对
Yeah.
你是哪里来的？
Where are you from?
达区 你呢？
Dodge. You?
墓碑镇 达区那儿有没有什么动静？
Tombstone. See any action up there?
没有
Uh-uh.
墓碑镇呢？
Tombstone?
也是一样 人们都安顿下来了
Same. People all settled down, like.
各地都是一样的
Same all over.
印地安爱人
Injun lovers!
放轻松点 那只是风声
Easy. Just wind.
我们会到达的
We'll get there.
不是那边的警报让我不安
It's not gettin' up there that bothers me.
是埋伏在那边的让我警觉
It's stayin' up there that I mind.
我们的左后方有人
Comin' up behind us on the left.
我不认为如此
I don't think so.
是二楼的窗子 窗帘动了
Second-storey window. Curtain moved.
我的位置不好 让他伸出头来
I'm not in a good position. Let him stick his neck out.
你也被悬赏吗？
You elected?
没有
No.
我就知道你还不错
I got nominated real good.
老兄 最好现在回头 可以省下很多麻烦
Boys, why don't you just turn around now - save yourselves a lot of trouble?
快到了 对吧？
Soon, huh?
接待小组已经准备好了
The reception committee is forming.
停
Hold it.
停在那儿
Hold it right there.
有何贵干
Anything wrong?
把马车调头 驾回去
Turn that rig around and get it down the hill.
这里需要六个人帮忙
I need six men up here.
呀呼
Yahoo!
伙计们 我请大家喝酒
Boys, the drinks are on me!
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
我想请你和你的朋友喝一杯
I'd like to buy you a drink. And your friend, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
你从哪里来的？
Where are you from?
是的 你要去哪里？
Oh, yeah. Where are you goin'?
谢谢你们的表演
Thanks for the free show.
不用客气
You're more than welcome.
伙计 你们刚才真棒 我就是活到一百岁也不会忘记
Boy, that was really something. I won't forget that if I live to be a hundred.
亨瑞 车要走了
Henry, the stage is leavin'!
好了 来了
All right, all right!
等我回去告诉福萝拉 她一个字都不会相信的
Wait till Flora hears about this. Y'know, she won't believe one word of it.
亨瑞 车要走了 快点
Henry! The stage! Come on!
这你留着喝
You keep this.
你到底要往哪去？
Where are you headed?
大概往南走吧
I'm drifting south, more or less.
你呢？
You?
我只是流浪
Just driftin'.
这里有事做么？
Any action here?
有啊 杂货店员和酒吧保镖
Yeah. Grocery clerk and bouncer
如果你愿意的话 对面酒馆在找保镖
in one of those bars across the street, if that's your taste.
啊
Ah.
耶
Yeah.
那么… 再见了
Well... see ya.
你… 叫什么名字？
Say, uh... what's your name?
麦克彬
Make it Vin.
你呢？
What's yours?
克里斯
Chris.
什么事？
Yes?
我们认为你是个可以信任的人
We think you are a man we can trust.
谢谢你们
Thank you very much.
我们需要你的帮助
We wish you to help us.
有个叫卡贝拉的人
There's this man, Calvera.
他是个强盗 一个凶手
A thief. A murderer.
他和他的伙伴抢了我们的食物 然后留下我们在那等着饿死
He and his men, they steal our food, and then they leave us to starve.
不但如此 我们的女人…
Not only that, but our women...
停一停
Wait, wait. Just a minute.
如果你们需要保护 为什么不找骑警队
If you need protection, go to the rurales.
我们去了两次
We did. Twice.
但是他们不能在一个小村庄里长期站岗 谁知道会有多久
But they can't station men in a small village for... who knows how long?
所以他们走了
So they left.
当他们走后 卡贝拉又回来 每年都是这样
And when they left, he came again - Calvera - and every year since.
他会一直这么做除非有人阻止他
He will do so until he is stopped.
请坐
Sit down.
我们需要帮助
We need help.
我们得买枪枝
We must buy guns.
但我们对枪真的一无所知
We know nothing about them.
你能替我们买枪吗？
Will you buy guns for us?
枪是既贵又难买
Guns are very expensive and hard to get.
你们为什么不雇人呢？
Why don't you hire men?
雇人？
Men?
枪手 现如今人命比枪还要贱
Gunmen. Nowadays men are cheaper than guns.
你会一起来吗？
Will you go?
如果你来帮助我们那就再好不过了
It will be a blessing if you help us.
抱歉 我不做善事的
Sorry, I'm not in the blessing business.
不 我们出高价
No, no. We offer more than that.
我们可以提供每日的膳食
We could feed you every day.
而且我们还有这些
And we have this.
那是什么？
What's that?
我们可以将这些变卖换成黄金
We can sell this for gold.
任何我们拥有的东西
Everything we own.
任何村子里值钱的东西
Everything of value in the village.
很多人出高价请我 但从来没有一个人拿出全部家当
I've been offered a lot for my work, but never everything.
这样够不够呢？
Will it be enough?
如果我们能把强盗打退…
You see, if we could drive the bandits away,...
村庄生活会变的很好的
..life could be very good in our village.
但依目前看来 我们自己勉强还可以过…
But as it is, we ourselves could stand it a little longer,...
但孩子们 他们因为饥饿而在哭叫
..but the children, they cry because they're hungry.
当你们开始这么做的时候你们明白这意味着什么吗
Do you understand what it means when you start something like this?
我们也会帮忙的 我们每一个人
We will fight, too. Every one of us.
当卡贝拉来时 教堂会响起钟声示警
When Calvera comes, the church bell will ring the alarm.
如果有枪的话 我们会用枪来战斗
We'll fight with guns, if we have them.
如果没有 我们用弯刀 斧 棒 任何东西
If we don't, with machetes, axes, clubs, anything!
你们一旦开战…
Once you begin,...
就得准备杀戮和更多的杀戮
..you have to be prepared for killing and more killing.
还得杀更多更多的人 直到敌人全部死
And still more killing - until the reason for it has gone.
我们了解
We understand.
我们已经考虑过这个了
We've considered that.
每个村民的想法都一致吗
Does every man in the village feel the same?
每一个人
Every man.
我会想办法帮你们
I'll see what I can do for you.
谢谢 你不知…
Gracias. You know...
等等 我并没说我会去
Now, wait. I didn't say I'II go.
我只把话传出去 说你们在雇人
I'll pass the word around that you're looking for men.
这里雇人并不难 每个人都带枪
It won't be hard to find men here. Everyone wears a gun.
当然 就像我们每天都穿裤子一样理所当然
Sure - same as they wear pants. That's expected.
但想找好的枪手 那又是另外一回事
But good men? That's something else again.
你怎么知道他们好不好？
How can you tell they are good?
我有方法
There are ways.
进来
Come in.
听说你在找人手
The word is out you're looking for men.
对 我们需要精于枪法的人
That's right. Men who are good with that.
我的枪法很好
I'm good with it.
快吗？
Fast?
考考我呀
Try me.
正想呢 站的近点
I aim to. Step in closer.
把手这样放
Now, hold your hands like that.
开始拍手
Now, clap.
拍快一点
Faster.
用最快速度拍
Now, as fast as you can.
现在你试试
Now you try it.
很年轻 而且很自负
Very young and... and very proud.
墓地里埋葬的都是又年轻又自负的小子
The graveyards are full of boys who were very young and very proud.
请进
Come in.
克里斯 不要耍花招
No tricks now, Chris.
哈瑞 真高兴又看到你
Harry! It's good to see you again.
哈啰 克里斯
Chris.
你怎么会在这种烂地方？
What are you doing in this dump?
我听说你在招兵买马
I heard you've got a contract open.
不是你这种高价人要做的
Not for a high-stepper like you.
一元美钞对我来说已经像床单一样大了
A dollar bill always looks as big to me as a bedspread.
这只是一点塞牙缝的小钱
It's just eating money.
哈瑞 一个金币 外加吃住而已 六个礼拜 为一些农夫工作
A gold eagle, room and board. Six weeks gunning for some farmers.
你这只老鸽子 话都不好听 但总知道好事
You old Cajun! You don't talk so good, but you always know what's goin' on.
哈瑞
Oh, Harry.
对不起 打扰一下
With your permission.
好了 表面话都说了 真情到底是什么？
All right. All that's on top. What's underneath?
就是我讲的
- Only what I told you.
是为黄金 牛 还是薪水袋？
Gold? Cattle? Payroll?
只有那些了
Only what I told you.
好 没关系 告诉我什么时候成事
Sure, never mind. Tell me when you can.
哈瑞 请你不要自做聪明
Harry, please don't understand me so fast!
我说没关系了 也算我一份
I said never mind. I'm in.
你这只老狗
You dirty dog!
请下注
Place your bets.
五
Five.
八
Eight.
又是八 庄家赢
Eights again. Ten at the point.
那位刚进来站在桌子旁的牛仔
The cowpoke that just walked in in the stovepipe chaps,...
我想请他喝杯酒
.. I'd like to buy him a drink.
好的 先生
Yes, sir!
看那边 又是一个我们要找的人 看他脸上的疤痕
Válgame Dios. There's one. Look at the scars on his face.
我们该找的是 给他疤痕的那个人
The man for us is the one who gave him that face.
嘿 你学的很快啊
Hey... you learn fast.
请各位下注
Next bet comin' up.
庄家赢
Crap.
下一位
Next man.
那边有位先生想请你喝杯酒
Gent over there wants to buy you a drink.
还好吧？
Vin.
你好
Howdy.
想请你喝杯酒
I'd like to buy you a drink.
来杯威士忌
Whiskey.
找到工作没？
Have you anything lined up?
找到了 我在一家杂货店找到一份工作
Yeah. I'm gonna take a job in a grocery store.
老板说我会成为最优秀的职员
Fella says I'm gonna make a crackerjack clerk.
最优秀的
Crackerjack.
如果这合你的胃口…
If that's your taste...
我是有听说边界乡村请人抗盗 但我不知道薪金多少
I heard of a job shooin' some flies away from a village, but I don't know the pay.
二十元
$20.
一个礼拜？
A week?
六个礼拜 整个工作
Six weeks: the whole job.
太可笑了
Well, that's ridiculous.
是说所有的报酬吗
You heard of anything?
是的
Yeah.
外带替他们赶些烦人的苍蝇
Shooing some flies away from a little village.
他们的村庄
Their village.
你们付二十元
It pays $20?
我现在正在找人
I'm looking for men right now.
不行 二十元不够我买子弹
No, it wouldn't even pay for my bullets.
我们的村庄是很穷的
Ours is a poor village.
我们了解 你可以从杂货店得到更多的钱…
We understand. You could get much more in a grocery store,...
而且又是个安稳长久的工作
..and it's good, steady work.
对
Yep.
你找到几个人了？
How many you got?
我们在找个叫欧瑞力的人
Looking for O'Reilly.
不认识这个人
Don't know his name,
不过可以去问后面砍柴做活的人
but there's a fella in back choppin' wood for his breakfast.
早
Mornin'.
我是哈瑞拉克斯的朋友
I'm a friend of Harry Luck's.
他告诉我你破产了
He tells me you're broke.
我做这些因为我是个古怪的百万富翁
Nah, I'm doing this because I'm an eccentric millionaire!
我这有份工作需要六个人 保护南方边界的一个小村
There's a job for six men, watching over a village, south of the border.
对方有多少人？
How big's the opposition?
三十个枪手
Thirty guns.
老兄 我很欣赏你对待如此显而易见的逆境的态度
I admire your notion of fair odds, mister.
哈瑞说你在特拉维斯县遇到过更大的困境
Harry tells me you faced bigger odds in the Travis County war.
他们那次付我六百块
Well, they paid me $600 for that one.
他说你在一个月内就把赫利摆平了
He said you got that Salinas thing cleared up.
他们那次付了我八百块
They paid me $800 for that one.
你的价码很高呀
You cost a lot.
对
Yeah...
我的价码是很高
That's right, I cost a lot.
他们肯付二十块
The offer is $20.
二十元？
$20?
目前那也算很多钱了
Right now, that's a lot.
我在哪里可以找到你
Where can I reach you?
在这
Right here.
我还是说他不行
I still say he can't.
我告诉你他行
And I tell you he can.
如果他这么说 那他是个骗子
If he claims that, he's a liar.
不要这么大声 他会听到的
Not so loud. He might hear you.
我才不管他听不听得到
I don't give a damn if he hears me or not.
我用两个月薪金赌他不能
I got two months' salary comin'. I'll bet it all it ain't so.
你赌不过我的
Well, you ain't bettin' with me.
我也是
Me either.
我只是告诉你他的话 我相信他
I told you what he said, and I believe him.
我们中有一个是笨蛋
Well, one of us is a fathead.
我们也知道是那一个
You can get good odds on which.
哈 哈
Ha! Ha! Ha!
瑞德 瑞德 醒来
Britt. Britt, wake up.
我在和你说话 看着我
I'm talkin' to ya! Look at me!
奥雷告诉我你的话 我说你骗人 你说呢？
Filene told me what you said. I say you're wrong. What d'you say?
哈 哈
Ha! Ha! Ha!
怎么了？在害怕吗？不敢告诉我你在骗人？
What's the matter? You afraid? Afraid to tell me I'm wrong?!
可以开始了
Call it.
看吧 我赢了
Well, you see, I won.
怎么样？
Well, how about it?
说啊
Well?
奥雷 怎么样？
Filene, how about it?
我不知道 我看很接近了
I don't know. It was mighty close.
接近？接近是什么意思？
Close? What d'you mean, close?
你们都有眼睛 你们也都亲眼看见了 我赢了
You all got eyes. You saw what happened. I won!
你告诉他们 我赢了对吧？
You tell 'em. I won, didn't I?
你输了
You lost.
你是个骗子
You're a liar.
我说你是个骗子
I said you're a liar!
我说你是个懦夫 也是个骗子
I said you're a coward and a liar!
起来 我们真正比试比试
Get up. Let's do it for real.
起来
Get up!
我说起来
Get up, I said!
不然我就这样开枪了
So help me, I'll let you have it right where you are.
开始吧
Call it!
我不想无故做这事
I want nothin' to do with this.
开始啊
Call it!
放下它吧 华莱士 忘记这事情吧
Drop it, Wallace. Forget it.
滚远一点
Get away from me.
可以开始了
Call it.
瑞德
Britt.
克里斯
Chris.
我想和你谈一下
Can I have a word with you?
你有运气吗
Did you have any luck?
找到一个很合适的人
Found a man who would have been perfect.
不管是玩刀或枪 都不能再好了 是不是很有趣
Gun or knife, you couldn't want any better. Wasn't interested.
钱呢？够吗？
The money? It wasn't enough?
他没有大叫要钱
He doesn't care a hoot about money.
你们这行也有不喜欢钱的？
A man in this line of work who doesn't care about money?!
我们这行也有很多种人 有些是爱钱如命
Men in this line of work are not all alike. Some care about nothing but money.
其他的 有些是因为私人原因 喜欢冒险
Others, for reasons of their own, enjoy only the danger.
有些是为了竞争
And the competition.
如果他玩刀和玩枪都是最好的 那他和谁比赛呢？
If he's the best with a knife and a gun, with whom does he compete?
他自己
Himself.
你
You.
我到处在找你
I've been looking for you!
我们在这里又怎么样
Uh-oh! What have we got here?
不怎么样
Never mind.
他知道
He knows.
他说… 拍手
Clap hands, he says.
拍手 让我们看看你有多快
Clap your hands, and let's see how fast you are.
拍手
Clap hands!
人们来找他 因为尊敬他
A man comes to him... cos he respects him,...
以能为他工作而骄傲
..cos he'd be proud to work with him.
他把我弄得像是个玩小孩游戏的笨蛋
He makes me look like two cents with some damned kids' game!
嘿 小子 说够了吧
Hey, kid, that's enough of that!
你走开 好么
You stay away from me, will ya?
来吧 你…
Come on, now,...
让我们来看你有多快
..and let's see how fast you are.
不要再玩游戏了 不要再玩什么拍手这种东西了
And no games, huh? No clapping hands - none of that stuff!
只要拨枪
Just draw.
来啊 来啊 拨枪
Come on. Come on, draw!
农夫 来啊
Campesino. Come on!
你说我是农夫？
You say campesino to me?!
给我滚远点 你这个臭农夫
You get out of my way, you dirt farmer!
你不明白我说什么吗？
You don't think I mean it, huh?
你… 你以为我只是说着玩吗
You... think I'm just talking, huh?
站起来
Hey... get up.
听到没？
Do you hear me?
站起来面对我
Get up and face me!
听到了没有？
Do you hear?!
嘿…
Hey,...
把我的枪给他
..give him my gun, huh?
很抱歉发生这事 朋友
Sorry this happened, friend.
让他睡饱
Let him sleep it off.
等他醒来后 把枪还给他
When he wakes up, let him have his gun back.
给他杯酒喝
And give him a drink.
我改变主意了
I changed my mind.
有个人在你房间 说是你的朋友
There's a man waiting in your room. Said he was a friend of yours.
还记得我吧？
Remember me?
记得
Yep.
你需要人手到墨西哥去 对吧？
You need men to do a job in Mexico.
对
That's right.
要多久？
How long?
四到六个礼拜
Four, six weeks.
也算我一份 这份工作付多少钱？
That ought to do it. How much does the job pay?
你不是在找约翰逊兄弟吗？
I thought you were looking for the Johnson brothers.
我找到他们了
I found them.
这个工作付多少钱？
How much does the job pay?
二十元 明早就出发
20. We leave tomorrow.
走前我要先拿钱
I'll have the money before I leave.
这正好付我欠的两天房钱
It'll just take care of my last two days' rent.
二十元？你一定住在很不错的地方
$20? You must be livin' in style.
是的
Yes.
我在这个烂店找到个最好的贮藏室
I have the most stylish corner of the filthy storeroom out back.
有一碟豆
That, and one plate of beans:
一天却要十元
$10 a day.
对 当你在逃亡的时候东西都会变得昂贵
Yeah, things do get high when they find out you're on the run.
镇外有个干洗店
There's a dry wash south of town.
我在那儿等你们
Pick me up there.
他是个很好的枪手
He's a good gun.
而且我们也不是去做善事的
And we aren't heading for a church social.
克里斯
Chris.
对 他在黎明时追上我们
Yeah. He picked us up at dawn.
知不知道是谁？
Any idea who it is?
是的 那个在酒吧的小子
Yeah. That kid from the saloon.
不用久等就有答案了
Won't take no for an answer.
他没有什么见识 是吗
Doesn't show much sense, does he?
我的脖子因为看他都酸了
I'm getting a stiff neck keepin' track of him.
如果不能忘记他 何不侧坐呢？
If you can't forget him, why don't you ride side-saddle?
算了 他不会再跟多久了
Ah, well... he won't last much longer.
是吗？
That so?
骑马沿途都是又湿又热 -真是一个笨蛋
Ridin' out there in all that dust and heat - what a chucklehead!
对 不像我们这么聪明
Yeah. Not smart like us!
对
Yep.
不知道我们的那个朋友有准备食物么
Suppose our friend over there has got anything to eat?
不如我带点食物过去
How about I bring him some?
他渴望的不是食物
Ah, it isn't food he's hungry for.
不然让我在他身上绑个罐子 这种夜晚根本看不见他
Then let me tie a can to his tail. Right now, he's like an itch I can't scratch.
不要理他 这是个自由国家
Ah, leave him alone. It's a free country.
是吗？
And it's his.
你知道吗？真是好笑 现在他走了 我还挺想他的
You know, it's funny. Now that he's gone, I kinda miss him.
大家都去哪里了？
Where is everybody?
他们都去哪儿了 托马斯
Where are they, Tomas?
路易 派克斯麦 丁米奇欧
Luis! Asunción! Demetrio!
阿米里欧 索太罗 这是什么待客方式啊？
Emilio! Sotero! What kind of a reception is this?
出来啊 在我们脸丢光钱赶紧出来欢迎啊
Come out! Come out and make them welcome, before we die of shame.
拉利欧 不要再叫了
Hilario, stop your shouting.
这是什么待客之道啊？他们是在干什么啊？
Do they call this a welcome? What are they thinking of?!
请进 你们一定很渴了
Come in. You must be thirsty.
你一定得原谅他们 他们只是这儿的农夫
You must excuse them. They are farmers here.
他们害怕所有人和所有事
They are afraid of everyone and everything.
他们既怕下很多雨又怕一点不下雨
They are afraid of rain, and no rain...
夏天可能太热 冬天可能太冷
The summer may be too hot, the winter - too cold.
母猪不生小猪 农夫怕会饿死
The sow has no pigs, the farmer is afraid he may starve.
生太多猪 他们又怕母猪会饿死
She has too many, he's afraid she may starve.
不需要抱歉 我们并没抱希望你们能隆重欢迎
There's no need to apologize. We didn't expect flowers and speeches.
明天是我们的建村周年纪念日
Tomorrow is the anniversary of the founding of the village.
他们会庆祝的 那时你就能看见他们更轻松的一面
They will be celebrating - then, you will see them in a better light.
谁敲的警钟？
Who sounded the alarm?
Who sounded the alarm?!
我敲的
I did.
谢谢各位父老乡亲来欢迎我们
Thank you, amigos, for coming out to greet us.
谢谢你们让我们看见 你美丽的脸
Thank you for letting us see your beautiful faces!
谢谢 谢谢 你们这些胆小鬼
Thank you, thank you, you chickens!
你们跑起来就像只笨鸡
You come running out like chickens!
我们骑了好多天的马 才到这个什么都不是的小村
We ride to this middle of nowhere.
我们准备冒着生命危险来帮助你们
We're ready to risk our lives to help you.
而你们呢？
And you?
你们躲藏起来
You hide from us!
藏起来了… 因为我们
Hide... from us!
不过当你们遇到危险又不一样了 对吧？
Ah... but it's a different story when you're in danger, huh?
你们可能损失那宝贵的农作物
You might lose your precious crops.
然后你们就会聚向我们？
Then you flock to us. Huh?
好吧 我们来了 我和我的战友
Well... we're here, my compadres and I.
我们会留下来的
And here we stay.
而你们…
And you?
你们得证明你们值得我们这么做
You prove to us that you're worth fighting for.
现在回你们家中回你们的工作 去吧 回去
Now get back to your houses, back to work. Go on! Go back.
我们会告诉你 何时和怎样去战斗 回去 你们全部都回去吧
We'll let you know when to fight and how to fight. Go back! All of you, go back!
回去啊
Go back!
现在我们有七个了
Now we're seven.
你知道吗 我曾到过一些女孩不是很美的城镇
You know, I've been in some towns where the girls aren't very pretty.
事实上 我到的一些城镇的女孩实在是丑
As a matter of fact, I've been in some towns where they were downright ugly.
但我这是第一次… 来到一个女孩都没有的城市
But this is the first time I've been in a town where there's no girls at all.
除了一些小孩
Except little ones.
你可知道 弄不好我们在这儿连一点乐子都没有
If we're not careful, we can have quite a social life here!
也没那么糟 昨天我和很多人排队到水泉边上
Oh, it's not so bad. I fell in with a fast crowd that hangs out near the fountain.
我们预测今日的天气在黄昏前不会变坏
We got to predictin' the weather for today and didn't break up till twilight.
停止音乐 把其它的烟花都拿出来
Stop the music! Bring out the other bull!
拉利欧
Hilario!
瑞德
Britt.
这个孩子刚看到三个卡贝拉的人 他们的马匹在旱谷
The boy saw three of Calvera's men. The horses are in the arroyo.
李
Lee.
抓一个活的回来
Get one alive.
好的
Yes.
我给你带路
I'll show you where.
提可 他知道旱谷在哪
Rico, he knows where the arroyo is.
我真的很抱歉 我不是故意的
I'm sorry, Britt. I didn't mean to spoil it.
闭嘴
Shut up!
噢… 这真是我看过最好的枪法
Oh... That... that was the greatest shot I've ever seen.
是最糟的
The worst.
我是想射马
I was aiming at the horse.
卡贝拉派了三个人来查探
Three men were sent by Calvera to spy.
他们肯定看到我们
It's almost certain they saw us.
不管他们看到什么 他们已经死了
Whatever they learned will be buried with them.
老天爷 如果他现在来…
¡Válgame Dios! If he comes now...
若他在附近就不用派人来了
He'd never send men ahead if he was near enough to see for himself.
所以我们还有时间来准备 外加另外一件事… 给他个惊喜
So we have time to get ready. And we have something else - surprise.
如果他胡乱闯进来 他绝对料不到我们的欢迎方式…
If he rides in with no idea of the reception we can prepare for him,...
我保证 我们一定会教训他
.. I promise you, we'll all teach him something about the price of corn.
瞄准…
Aim,...
压…
..squeeze,...
开枪
..cock.
瞄准…
Aim,...
压…
..squeeze,...
开枪
..cock.
专心 现在你失去了第一次机会 你不会有第二次机会
Settle down. Now, you miss the first chance, you may not get a second.
将它紧贴你的肩膀 否则只会有两件事情发生
Get that butt tight in your shoulder. If you don't, two things will happen.
第一 你会浪费子弹 第二 你会打断自己的手臂
One: you'll waste a bullet. Two: you'll break your arm.
现在 闭上眼睛 由这里瞄准直到目标
Now, close your eye. Aim from here, to here, to the target.
开枪
Fire.
打那块石头？
That rock?
不 打你要杀的人
No, that man you're gonna kill.
好
Good!
我们有更多的枪 我们会做到的
If only we had more guns, think what we could do!
你们会得到更多的枪的
You'll get more guns.
怎么弄？
How?
跟弄这些枪的方法一样 从卡贝拉手下啊
The same way you got these. Calvera's men.
来侦探的人带着这些
The ones who spied on us brought them.
就像圣经中 带着礼物朝圣的三王
Like three kings bearing gifts.
如果卡贝拉不来的话…
If Calvera does not come now, after all of this,...
你们就白费力气了
..what a waste!
卡贝拉这人像狐狸一样 对吧？
A pretty foxy fellow, this Calvera, eh?
先生 不是像狐狸 像一只郊狼
Señor, not a fox. A coyote!
他怎么知道有金矿的？
How did he ever find out about the gold mine?
金矿？
Gold mine?
什么金矿啊 先生？
What gold mine, señor?
就是那座山里的金矿啊
You know, the one in the mountains.
在我们山里？
In our mountains?
我们这附近没有金矿
We never had a gold mine around here.
对了 我记得了 是一座银矿
Say, come to think of it, it was a silver mine.
发生了什么事
Whatever happened to it?
这附近也没有银矿
We have no silver mine either.
我是指很久以前那座
I mean in the old days.
这里从来都没有过
Not at any time.
你是从哪听到这些金矿和银矿的
Where did you hear of this gold and silver, hm?
好了 伙计们 多干活少说话
All right, come on, boys. More work, less talk, huh?
来啊
Toro.
¡Toro!
过来呀 小牛
Come on, little bull!
来呀
Toro.
别过来 你一动手我就会杀了你
You do anything to me and I'll kill you while you are doing it.
你可真让我吃惊
You almost took my eye out!
让我走 放手
Let me go. Let me go!
你敢咬我 我就咬你
Oh, you bite me and I'll bite you!
我真想把你扔到水里
I got a good mind to throw you in the water.
我会用石头打碎你 将你的头割下来
Smash you with a rock! Cut your head off!
闭嘴 闭上你的嘴
Shut up. Shut up!
其他的人呢？
Where are the others? Huh?
我不会告诉你
I'll never tell you.
看我找到什么
Look what I found.
她是谁？
Who is she?
是我们村里的人
From our village.
村里没女人就是这个原因 你们把她们藏起来了
So that's where they were. You hid them.
肯定是他们把她们藏起来了 但她不肯说在哪里
Sure they hid them. But she won't tell where.
她们害怕 她怕我们全部人
They're afraid. She's afraid of me, you, him... all of us.
这些臭农夫 她们的家人说我们会强暴她们
Farmers! Their families told them we'd rape them.
虽然这也有可能
Well, we might.
我觉得你们也不该这么的肯定
In my opinion, though, you might have given us the benefit of the doubt.
但是… 随便你们了
But... just as you please.
你既然碰上了… 为什么不多带几个回来？
As long as you were out there, why didn't you bring 'em all in?
为了什么？让她们留在那儿
What for? Leave them out there.
让卡贝拉找到她们 他会好好照顾她们的
Let Calvera find them. He'll take good care of them.
把她们带回来
Bring them in.
你带他去找
Show him the way.
女士
Ma'am.
走吧 小天使
Come on, little angel!
真善变
Gently, boy.
又温柔
Gently.
你们每次为我们预备的这些晚餐是在是太好了
I can't tell you how wonderful it was for you señoritas to fix dinner for us.
食物怎么样？
How's the food?
很棒
Great.
鸡肉 墨西哥菜和西班牙饭 看起来真的不错
Chicken enchiladas, carne asada and Spanish rice. Looks good.
对啊 这些人真会烧饭 过来 还有很多
These people really know how to cook. Dig in, there's tons of it.
你们知道从我们来后 村民都在吃什么吗？
Do you know what the villagers have been eating since we got here?
粟米饼和一些豆子 只有这些
Tortillas and a few beans, that's all.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
谢谢 不客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
嘿 你家里有没有个漂亮的姐姐？
Do you have an older, grateful sister at home?
没有 先生 谢谢你
No, sir. Many thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
谢谢
Many thanks.
1 2 3 4
One, two, three, four.
1 2…
One, two,...
3 4
..three, four.
1 2 3 4
One, two, three, four.
好 用力
Squeeze.
丹尼尔 我不是叫你捏紧吗？
Miguel, didn't I tell you to squeeze? Hm?
就像挤羊奶一样 丹尼尔
Just like when you're milking a goat, Miguel.
我很紧张
It's that I get excited.
那就想办法不要紧张
Well, don't get excited!
这次捏紧 慢慢的 但要捏紧
Now, this time, squeeze. Slowly, but squeeze.
好的… 捏紧
All right... squeeze.
用力
Squeeze!
我教你怎么做 不要开枪
I'll tell you what. Don't shoot the gun.
这样拿着枪 将它当作棒来使用 可以吗
You take the gun like this and you use it like a club. All right?
好
Right.
休息
Flaco!
谢谢你们啦
Muchas gracias.
两位午安
Good afternoon.
你好
Howdy.
好了 我们是来帮你搬到村里的
We've come to move you into the village.
搬进村里？我？
Move into the village?! Me?!
每一个住在村外的人
Everybody who lives outside.
不行
Oh, no.
你住这的话 我们没法保护你的
We can't protect you out here.
你可以先住在鲁耶的家
Rojas is makin' room for you in his home.
他？和他谈话会把我闷死
Rojas?! His conversation would bore me to death!
好 但…
Yeah, well, uh...
那住别人家好了
..maybe somebody else, huh?
他们全都是农夫
They are all farmers.
农夫除了肥料和女人外什么都不谈的
Farmers talk of nothing but fertilizer and women.
我永远也没办法像他们一样对肥料感兴趣
I've never shared their enthusiasm for fertilizer.
至于女人… 自从我83岁后 就没兴趣了
As for women... I became indifferent when I was 83.
我仍要留在这里
I am staying here.
那… 那卡贝拉来时怎么办？
Yeah, well, uh... what are you gonna do when Calvera comes?
我这把年纪有些刺激也好
At my age, a little excitement is welcome.
不要担心 他为什么要杀我？
Don't worry. Why would he kill me?
子弹也要花钱啊
Bullets cost money.
好吧 随便你了
All right. Have it your way.
你多替自己担心吧
You worry about yourself.
你可准备好了？
Are you ready for him?
万一他现在来了怎么办？
What if he comes now, eh?
我想起一个从十楼跳下的男人
It's like that fella who fell off a ten-storey building.
他怎么了？
What about him?
他一边掉 还一边对自己说:"目前还不错 "
As he was falling, people on each floor heard him say "So far, so good."
目前还不错
So far, so good!
他们首先会看见那些壕沟
First of all, they'll see that ditch.
谷物要多些水
More water for the corn.
有很多新墙
Awful lot of new walls.
这是文明的进步
Civic improvements.
克里斯…
Hey, Chris,...
那张网呢
..what about that net, eh?
只要他不特意的去看…
Well, if he's not looking for it...
如果他来时没起疑
If he rides in unsuspecting.
"如果" 老兄
If, brother!
"如果"
If!
对
Yeah.
Yeah!
我早该料到的 当我的手下没回来时 我就该料到的
I should have guessed. When my men didn't come back, I should have guessed.
你们有多少为他们工作
How many of you did they hire?
足够对付你的
Enough.
新的墙
New wall!
很多新墙 到处都是
There are lots of new walls. All around.
可是挡不住我的
They won't keep me out.
它们是为了 把你们留在此而建的
They were built to keep you in.
你们听到没？我们中埋伏了
Did you hear that? We're trapped!
四十个人都踏入陷井了 就被这三个人捕捉
All forty of us! By these three.
还是四个？他们没钱雇更多的帮手了
Or is it four? They couldn't afford to hire more than that.
我们的报酬都很微薄
We come cheaper by the bunch.
五个
Five!
即使五个我们也没放在眼里
Even five won't give us too much trouble.
只要你走就没有任何麻烦
There won't be any trouble - if you ride on.
走？
Ride on?
我会到深山过冬
I'm going into the hills for the winter.
我到哪替我手下找食物？
Where am I going to get food for my men?
去种啊
Buy it or grow it.
或去做工挣钱啊
Or maybe even work for it!
七个人
Seven!
可惜你们根本没有替我解决问题
Somehow, I don't think you've solved my problem.
替你解决问题又不是我们的工作
Solving your problems isn't our line.
我们在商量 朋友
We deal in lead, friend.
我也是 我们是同行 对吧？
So do I. We're in the same business, huh?
只是对手
Only as competitors.
何不成为伙伴呢？
Why not as partners?
或许我分一半给你们
Suppose I offer you equal shares?
分什么
In what?
任何事 连吃的都是一样
Everything. To the last grain.
那村里的人呢？他们怎么办？
And the people in the village? What about them?
那就看你们了
I leave it to you.
干我们这行的 还担心这种小事
Can men of our profession worry about things like that?
又不是做宗教的
May even be sacrilegious.
如果上帝不眷顾他们 他就不会给他们羊群
If God didn't want them sheared, he would not have made them sheep.
你说呢？
What do you say?
还是离开吧
Ride on.
听到没？索太罗
You hear that, Sotero?
听到他说的话没有？
You hear what he said?
叫我们离开
Ride on.
对着我
To me!
你最好在我发脾气前 赶快叫他们离开
You tell him to ride on before I become angry.
听到了没有？
Him, and the others!
因为如果我这次空手而归…
Because, if I leave with empty hands,...
下次他们还是得听我的话 因为我会再回来的
..everybody in this village will answer to me - when I come back!
你不会回来的
You won't come back.
为什么不会？
Why not?
因为你没有枪
You won't have any guns.
现在你们全部把枪丢出来
Take them off right now and drop them.
宽容 这是我犯的第一个错误
Generosity. That was my first mistake!
我多留一点东西给这些村民 他们却跑去雇人来给我找麻烦
I leave these people a little bit extra and they hire these men to make trouble.
不过 小心了… 你们迟早要付出代价的
It shows you... sooner or later, you must answer for every good deed.
你当时怕的躲在石头后面
You were safe.
我却在外面向死神挑战 十个像恶魔似的强盗
I was face to face with them as they rode toward me. Ten of them, screaming.
你上次说只有五个
The last time you told it, it was five!
他的数字变的 跟兔子繁殖一样快
They multiply like rabbits!
十个 有十个
Ten. Ten!
嘿
Yeh-hey!
听我说 他们这次可受到教训了
They got a good kick in the behind.
他们若敢再来 我们就一网打尽
If they try it again, they'll get another!
我们会将他们碎尸万段
We'll tear them to pieces.
把他们全都抓住 然后弄死
We'll bury them all. Calvera too, huh?!
有没有他们的踪迹？
Any sign of 'em?
没有
No.
我们惨了
That is bad luck.
你可能想像得到？他们像老鼠似的逃走了
Can you imagine? I knew him when he was a mouse!
我这辈子还没这么怕过 我的膝盖都冻住了
I was never so frightened in my life. My knees were like jelly.
我可没看出来
I would never have guessed it.
他从此不敢来碰我们了
Well, he'll leave us alone from now on.
你真的这么想？当然
You think so? Of course.
他会到别处去的 到别的村落去
He'll go away. There are other villages -
其他村落不会像我们这样做
other villages that don't sting the way we do.
先生
Señor!
各位… 我为我们的好朋友干杯
Neighbors... I drink to our friends.
他们几个和我们一起并肩做战 他们会永远活在我们心中
They armed us, fought at our sides, and will forever live in our hearts.
这么说他们并没有离开
They haven't gone, then.
有没有看到枪火？
See the gun flashin'?
没有
No.
我看那边有两个人
I make it two of them.
三个
Three.
那小鬼迟早会把命给玩掉
Fool kid's gonna get his head blown off.
吉可 不要乱来
Chico! Stay put.
三个？
Three?
三个
Three.
赖利 你有没有看到他们？
O'Reilly? Do you see them?
没有 他们躲得老远 在树后边
No... They're too far back in the trees.
克里斯 干什么？
Chris. Yeah?
我想办法到石头那边去 你们替我掩护
Try and make it up to those rocks. I'll cover you.
吉可 你守后面
Chico... cover the back door.
退回去
Get back!
退回去 快啊
Get back! Go on!
你们是怎么一回事 听不到我的话吗
What's the matter? Don't you hear so good?
乖乖的蹲下来 不要乱动
Get down. Now stay down!
傻孩子 你们很可能会受伤的
Crazy kids! You might have been hurt.
你也是一样
So might you.
这是两回事
It's not the same thing.
这是我的工作
This is my work.
这也是我的工作
It's our work, too.
每个人都叫我们躲起来 到村外躲着
Everyone tells us "Hide! Get back! Stay out of sight!"
但我们并不怕
But we're not afraid.
他真的很勇敢 这是事实
He's very brave. It's the truth.
他也是 我们全是 村中每个男孩都很勇敢
So is he. We all are - every boy in the village.
我们自己开过会了 大家抽签 而我们抽到了你
We had a meeting and we drew straws and we got you.
抽到了我？这是什么意思？
You got me? What d'you mean, you got me?
如果你被杀 我们会拿枪为你报仇
If you get killed, we avenge you.
我们会负责在你的墓前献花
And we see to it that there's always fresh flowers on your grave.
你们对我真是太好了
That's a mighty big comfort!
看 我早就说他会喜欢的
I told you he would appreciate that.
我要是没死 你们可别失望
Don't you kids be too disappointed if your plans don't work out.
不会的 你若活下来 我们也一样的高兴
We won't. If you stay alive, we'll be just as happy.
也许更高兴
Maybe even happier.
也许
Maybe.
你看到他们没？
Can you see them?
没有
No.
你的…
Do your, uh,...
开战之前 你手会不会出汗？
..hands sweat before a fight?
每一次都会
Every time.
我现在也是
Mine are sweatin' now.
有趣
Funny...
手在出汗
Hands sweat,...
口在发干
..mouth is dry.
本来应该是反过来的
You'd think it would be the other way around.
你会不会… 觉得我讲话很烦？
Does my... talking annoy you?
嗯
Mm-mm.
这实在是因为…
It's because I'm...
我很害怕
.. I'm frightened, you know?
我明白 你一定在想 早知道就服从卡贝拉算了
Yeah. I guess you kinda wish you'd given your crops to Calvera, huh?
对…
Yes...
不对
..and no.
两种感觉都有吧
Both at the same time.
但当我一想起那些…
Yes, when I think of,...
他会怎么做
..of what he might do.
不对 当我想起今早的感觉
No, when I remember the feeling in my chest this morning...
当我看到他走远
..as I saw him run away.
逃离我们
From us.
他那么的生气
Man,...
值得为了那种感觉而死
..that's a feeling worth dying for!
你… 你有没有这种感觉过？
Have you ever... felt something like that?
已经很久很久没有过了
Not for a long, long time.
我…
I, uh,...
我真羡慕你
..envy you.
你在干什么？
What are you doing here?
你不能再做刚才那种傻事了
You shouldn't do things like you did.
回去
Go back.
你不可以再冒险
You mustn't take foolish chances.
好 我不会的 你快回去吧
All right, I won't. But go back.
受伤了吗
Does it hurt?
什么？
What?
不痛
No.
那就好 但我以为…
I'm sorry I did it, but I thought...
你知道我想什么的
You know what I thought.
是 是 我知道
Yes, yes. I know.
我不是怕你们 而是我爸爸…
I wasn't afraid of you. It's my father.
他说离这些人远一点
He says "Stay away from those men."
他们很凶狠 都很残酷
"They are brutes. They are cruel."
他是对的 知道吗？他是对的
He's right. Do you know that? He's right.
立刻回家
Well... go back home now.
他错了
He is wrong.
无论如何 快回家吧
Well... go home anyway,...
在他在这里找到你之前
..before he finds out you're here.
他已经知道了
He already knows.
他说会为我的不害羞而责罚我
He said he'd punish me for being so shameless.
但我不在乎
But I don't care.
他们消灭了他们 全消灭了
They got them. They got them all!
好
Result.
今晚他们会不会再来？
Do you think they'll try that again?
我想会的
I doubt it.
不过他一动 我们就会知道的
For all they know, we're still out there ready to jump them.
他没退走？卡贝拉没撤退吗？
He didn't go. Calvera didn't go?
天下有这种容易的事吗？
Did you think it would be that easy?
我们现在怎么办？
What do we do now?
你说呢
Well, what do you say?
我？
Me?
我们是替你工作啊
We work for you, you know.
除了等以外 还能做什么？
What else is there to do but... wait?
现在该卡贝拉了
It's Calvera's move.
对
Right.
那你最好代替那些守备的人 他们一定累了
Now you'd better replace the guards. They must be tired.
如果你是卡贝拉… 怎样？
If you were Calvera,... Yes?
你会走吗 是吗
..you'd go away, wouldn't you?
假如我们给你利益 你会走
If you'd paid the price we make him pay.
是的 我会 只是…
Yes, I would, only...
只是什么？
Only what?
只是我不是卡贝拉
Only I'm not Calvera.
拿着步枪 把强盗们打昏
Take the rifles and the bandoleras and pass 'em out.
该我们去守了
Now, let's get out there on duty.
女人们弄食物
Food, woman.
他们一定饿了
They'll be hungry.
那真是… 那真是世上最棒的…
That was... that was the greatest...
小鬼 给你一顶新帽子
New hat for you, sonny.
嘿
Hey!
好不好看？
How do I look? Huh?
比以前好多了
Big improvement.
你可知道 以后他们会为你和这帽子编首歌
You know what? They'll make up a song about you and this hat.
农村人都喜欢大事件而编歌 然后千古流传
Villages like this make up a song about every big thing. They sing them for years.
你觉得值得吗？
Do you think it's worth it?
难道你不觉得
Don't you?
只要你会玩枪
It's only a matter of knowing how to shoot a gun.
这根本不重要
Nothing big about that.
嘿… 你怎么可以这么说？
Hey... how can you talk like this?
你能有今天都是因为你的枪 难道不是吗？
Your gun has got you everything you have. Isn't that true?
嗯？
Mm?
难道不是吗？
Well, isn't that true?
对 是真的
Yeah, sure. Everything.
你可以用姓氏称呼那些酒保和庄家
After a while you can call bartenders by their first name.
那大概是两百个
Maybe 200 of 'em.
租房住要五百元 在平价餐馆吃饭要一千
Rented rooms you live in: 500. Meals you eat in hash houses: 1,000.
家 没有 老婆 没有 孩子
Home: none. Wife: none. Kids:
也是没有
none.
前途 零
Prospects: zero.
我还漏了什么吗？
Suppose I left anything out?
有
Yeah.
有能够留恋的地方？没有
Places you are tied down to: none.
有令你牵挂的人？没有
People with a hold on you: none.
有令你尊敬的人？没有
Men you step aside for: none.
有令你心折的人？
Insults swallowed:
没有
none.
有没有敌人？没有
Enemies: none.
没有敌人？
No enemies?
没有活着的敌人
Alive.
这种数学是我最喜欢的一种
Well! This is the kind of arithmetic I like!
对 我在你这年纪时也是一样
Yeah, so did I at your age.
把这些分开懂得使用它们的人
Give these to someone who knows how to use them.
好
Yeah.
为何不去问卡贝拉他今晚想怎么打
Why don't you ask Calvera what he has in mind for tonight?
对 好主意 问到后我亲自替你编首歌
Yes, do that. And I'll write a song for you myself.
曼德士 罗兰士 菲力普都死了
Andrés, Lorenzo and Felipe never came back.
死了三个
That's three.
罗曼多死在广场
Armando in the plaza.
四个了
That's four.
阿曼和迪派裘在通道
And Jorge and Memo in the pass,
死在网子那边
where they were caught by that cursed net.
这些天杀的
Damn them!
五个 不 六个
Five and six.
阿米力欧死在墙旁
Emilio going over the wall.
七个
Seven.
葛才士死在喷泉旁
José near the fountain.
八个
Eight.
还有哥力欧也死在喷泉旁
Gregorio near the fountain.
九个人了
That's nine.
九个人
Nine.
再加上佛东尼欧死在水渠边
Fortuno by the water ditch.
李宽在田边被砍成了碎片
Rico in the fields, where they slashed him to pieces!
这是… 十个 不 十一个
That's... 10 and 11.
继续啊
Go on.
说啊
Talk.
说 说
Talk! Talk!
它们全死了 忘掉这事儿吧
They're all dead anyway. Forget about them.
我们仍有很多人为他们报仇
There's still plenty of us here... to make them pay.
那群笨蛋
Our friends down below.
不要
Please, no!
没事吧 你没事的
It's all right. You're all right.
做梦了而已 只是个恶梦罢了
You had a dream. Just a bad dream.
不用害怕
Have no fear.
"不用害怕"？
"Have no fear"?
这是我常告诉自己的
My very words.
每天都得说上一万次
10,000 times a day.
先生 不要惩罚你自己
Señor, don't punish yourself.
一个能打了这么多仗的人 一定是个很勇敢的人
A man who has fought so many times... You must have great courage.
直到有一天你失去了你所有的胆量
Until the day you lose your nerve.
你可以感觉得到
You feel it.
摆脱不掉的…
And then you wait,...
当你的子弹慢于对方时
..for the bullet in the gun that is faster than yours.
先生 不要这样
Señor, don't.
那些自己骗自己的话
And the lies you tell, to fool yourself.
没有敌人
No enemies:
仍活着
alive.
我已经数不清我的敌人了
I have lost count of my enemies.
但你现在是和朋友在一起
But you're with friends now.
是的
Yes.
和世上一群最笨的人
The final, supreme idiocy:
在这里藏身
comin' here to hide.
逃兵  躲在战场的中央
The deserter... hidin' out in the middle of a battlefield.
一个
One.
我曾经可以捉住全部的
There was a time when I woulda caught all three.
我们知道什么叫害怕
We know what fear is.
我们一辈子都活在害怕里
We live with it all our lives.
只有死人才不会怕
Only the dead are without fear.
提可
Rico!
马上就来了 妈妈
One minute, Mother!
我们花十分装睡 然后再回来值勤
Ten minutes to pretend we're asleep, and then we'll be back on duty.
好不好啊
All right, Bernardo?
好 不过你不行
Yes, but not you, Juan.
你太小了 走吧
You're too young. Come on.
罗那多欧瑞力？
Bernardo O'Reilly!
被人领养了吗
You've been adopted.
这是我的本名
Yeah, it's my real name.
一半是墨西哥人 一半是爱尔兰
Mexican on one side, Irish on the other, and me in the middle.
现在小心看守 我们走
Now, watch carefully. Here we go.
看到没 三个在那边
See? All three, right side up.
你做得到吗？
Think you can do it?
当然 很容易
Of course. That's very easy.
你想赌一赌吗 下点小赌注
Would you, uh... care to make a friendly wager? A little bet?
先生 你知道我们很穷的
You know we have no money.
不一定要钱 其他的也行
It doesn't have to be money.
什么都可以 那种卡贝拉找不到的也行
Whatever you have hidden away, buried out where Calvera can't find it.
-例如珠宝 -珠宝
Like jewels. Jewels?!
对 他们说山里挖掘出很多珠宝
Yeah. They tell me a lotta precious stones have been dug out of the mountains.
猫眼石 翡翠 蓝宝石
Opals, emeralds... sapphires.
对 对 这是真的
Oh, yes. Yes, that's very true.
铁打的事实
There's no denyin' it.
那你的意思呢？
Well, then!
不对 不对 当你弄好时 他们会这样站着
No! When you're finished, they should all be right side up.
让我试试看
Let me try it again, eh?
关于那些宝石 他们在哪里找到的
About those precious stones... Where are they found?
就如你所说的 在山中
As you say, señor, in the mountains.
在山的哪一个地方
Where in the mountains?
那我就不能告诉你了
That I couldn't tell you.
我找到了 那边
There! I got it!
不要管它了 别管了 你为什么不能告诉我？
Never mind that. Why can't you tell me?
因为我从来都没发现过宝石
Because I never have found any precious stones.
等一下 你说阿芝台克人的珠宝 当西班牙人来时埋藏在山中
Wait. You mean Aztec treasure buried in the hills, from when the Spaniards came?
对 是阿芝台克人的珠宝 你在哪里找到的
That's exactly what I mean. Aztec treasure. Have you found some?
要是我有 我就不会坐在这了
Would to God we had! I would not be sitting here.
我会住在城里一栋皇宫中
I'd be living in a big city, in a palace.
那告诉我 卡贝拉干什么老来抢你们？
Then tell me this - how come Calvera keeps hangin' around here?
卡贝拉 他已经快完了 明早就会走了
Calvera... We've seen the end of him. He'll be gone in the morning.
不 他不会走的
No, he will not.
他哪也不会去
He won't go anywhere.
你为什么这么说？
Why do you say that?
卡贝拉不是在为冬天存粮而担心
Calvera isn't worried about food for winter.
他是为他们已经三天没吃而发愁
He's worried about the food his men haven't eaten for the last three days.
看起来玉米的价钱又涨了
The price of corn is going up.
他们饿坏了
They're starving.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know?
又饿又穷
Starving and broke.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know?!
噢…
Oh...
我到过那边
I've been up there.
我们最好准备一下
Well, we'd better be ready for them.
因为他们已走投无路
Because they gotta die or win.
我只担心一件事 他们赢了怎么办？
Válgame Dios if they do win.
他们不会赢
They won't win.
你是神吗 那么肯定
Are you God, that you can say for sure?
我们被包围了 人手不够 该怎么办呢
We're surrounded. Outnumbered. What are we to do?
继续打
Keep on fighting.
你想看我们一个一个被杀死吗？
Do you want to see us killed off one by one?
这可不是我们雇你们来的原因
That is not what you were hired for.
你一旦开始 就不能停手
Once you start, there's no stopping.
这你也知道的 我也告诉他们了
You understood that, and I told him!
我才不管呢
I don't care.
离开这里 全部都走 骑上马离开这里
Go away. All of you. Get on your horses and go.
让卡贝拉把食物带走
Let Calvera have the food.
给他拿他要的东西
Give him what he wants.
最起码我们还活着
At least we'll be alive.
闭嘴 听我说
Quiet! And listen to me!
不行 他们当然会说战斗下去
No! It is easy for them to say fight.
他们又没有女儿 儿子 老婆
They have no sons, no daughters, no wives.
走 趁还不太迟时赶快离开
Go. Now, before it's too late.
这是你们想要的吗？
Is that what you want?
回答我
Answer me!
谁要继续打 谁要投降 我现在要知道
Who's for going on and who's for giving up? I want to know now.
不要傻了 你们会把这村子变成坟场
Don't be fools! You'll turn our village into a graveyard.
叫他们走 这是我们唯一可做的事
Tell them to go. It's the only thing for them to do.
我会告诉你我还可以做什么
I'll tell you what I can do.
我可以杀掉第一个说投降的人
I can kill the first man who so much as whispers a word about giving up.
带头的人 我会打爆他的头
The very first man, so help me, I'll blow his head off!
我们已经开始这场仗了… 我们非打赢它不可
We started this fight... and we're gonna finish it!
你们帮不帮都无所谓
With or without you.
我不想说我们太高估自己
I'm not sayin' we bit off more than we can chew,...
可是我必须这么说
..but we oughta talk about what we're gonna do.
我们要小心研究应该怎么做 要理智地行动
We start acting like we had some good sense.
我们当初是说可以找到人手 正好可以打倒卡贝拉
We figured to raise the ante just enough to make Calvera play someplace else.
我们预计错误
We figured wrong.
因为我们的想法得不到支持
We're the only game in town.
不会有人响应他们
A man can't call 'em all.
我也没说有用
I didn't say he could.
只是有时人该顺天行事… 不然就会完蛋
All I'm saying is that sometimes you bend with the breeze... or you break.
你想走？
D'you wanna go?
是时候收拾离开了 反正我们走后村子也不会比以前更糟
There comes a time to get out. The village will be no worse off than before we came.
你忘了一件事 我们是有合约的
You forget one thing. We took a contract.
任何法庭都不会受理的
It's not the kind courts enforce.
那只是让你要坚持下去
That's just the kind you've gotta keep.
这是个很高贵的想法 可是情况并不看好…
A noble thought, but the way things are right now,...
我也不知道
.. I don't know.
风险太大了
The odds are too high.
是很大 那我们走？
Much too high. Then we go?
不行
No.
我们将风险降低
We lower the odds.
一直骑过那个坡…
Right up into the hills,...
经过看守的人…
..past the men on guard,...
走进他们的营区
..right into their camp.
和他们一起坐下来抽根烟 谈了些事情
I sat there, I smoked a cigarette with them, we discussed a few things.
我们… 你知道的
We... you know...
然后卡贝拉突然出现了
All of a sudden, there was Calvera himself.
就站在我身边 当我把消息带回来时
Right beside me. When I brought back the news,...
你真该看到他们的脸 还有克里斯的
..you should have seen the look I got from Britt - and from Chris.
他们可是见过大风大浪的人 而且自己也做过不少大事
They have seen a thing or two in their time, and done them too.
可不是那种 很简单就能讨好的人
They're not men you can impress easily. Oh, no.
当他们那样看我时 我知道我总算成为他们的一员了
But when they looked at me, I knew I was one of them at last.
那么…
Well,...
你最好也好好的看看我
..you'd better take a look at me, too.
我像生活在这种地方的人吗？
Am I the kind of man who'd live in a place like this? Hm?
把生命浪费在种田上
Digging my life away out in the fields?
我 一个农夫？一个穷人？
Me, a farmer - a peasant?
你知道我在说什么吗
You know what I'm saying, huh?
不管克里斯 哈瑞 其他的人去哪里
Wherever they go - Chris, Vin, Britt, the others -
我都要和他们一起去
I go with them.
别以为你的想法做法
And if you think you, or anything you do,
会改变我 放弃吧
could make me change my mind, forget it.
我希望你明白这点
I want you to understand that.
我… 我要你先了解这事…
I... want you to understand that...
这个…
..this...
除了这个以外 我什么都不能给
..will get you nothing but this.
我们要去偷袭卡贝拉…
We're going to hit Calvera,...
或许骑走他的一些马
..maybe drive off some of his horses.
如果他要进攻 只能步行
Then if he attacks, he'll be on foot.
我和你们一起去 我熟知地形
I'll go with you. I know every rock.
不 你留下 你是这里的司令
No, you stay. You're in charge here.
你可以信任我的
You can count on me.
好吧
I know I can.
他们已经出发去袭击村子了
They've left to hit the village.
不可能的
No.
我们一定会听到枪声的
We'd have heard shots.
他们已经走了
They've gone.
晚安
Good evening.
随便乱动 你们通通会死
You'll be dead. All of you!
就像这样
Like that!
如果你不想死的话
If that's what you want.
我们还有选择的余地吗？
Do we have a choice?
当然有
Of course.
坐下
Sit down.
我们来谈谈
Let's talk.
情况逆转了 对吧？
Things are turned around now, uh?
你在奇怪对不对？
You're wondering how.
你的朋友已经不太喜欢你们了
Your friends, they don't like you very much any more.
你强迫他们做太多决定了
You force them to make too many decisions.
跟着我他们只有一个选择
With me... only one decision.
服从我
Do what I say.
其实你是不该太吃惊的
You should not be surprised.
谢谢我的好朋友索太罗 是他安排我们进来的
My good friend Sotero, he arranged to let me come in.
明白了吧
Understand?
好了 现在…
Well, anyway,...
这是交易
..to business!
我可以杀掉你们全部的 同意吗
I could kill you all. You agree?
最起码 没有不同意的吧
Well... you don't disagree.
不管怎样 我并不想杀你们
Anyway, I don't want to kill you.
为什么这么大方？
Why so generous?
实际上 他们听说
Practical. They hear about it up north.
你有朋友会找我麻烦
Maybe some friends of yours make more trouble for me.
一个人不会没有麻烦的
A man who never wants no trouble.
我们这里有句话
We have a saying here.
一个从小偷家偷东西的人 会坐牢一百年
A thief who steals from a thief is pardoned for 100 years.
这是什么意思呢？
All right, what does that leave?
我原谅你们了
Only one thing. I pardon you.
走吧
Ride on.
就像这样？
Just like that?
就这样
Mm, just like...
我会帮你 你们要食物…
I'll make it easy for you. You want food?
我给你们食物
Give them food.
水？好 给你们水
Water? All right. Water.
马？已经都准备好了
Horses? Saddled and waiting.
枪？
Guns?
枪 枪和枪带都得取下来放在这边
The guns... the gun belts, you take off and put here now.
那这些人呢？
What about these people?
这些人的命运 无关我是否杀你
What happens to these people will happen whether I kill you first or not.
算是一份小小礼物好吗？
Just a little gesture, huh?
让这些人瞧瞧谁是真正的老大
To show these people who the real boss is.
只要你们离开此地 我就还你枪
You go, then I give you the guns back.
我知道你不会用那些枪对付我的
I know you won't use those guns against me.
只有疯子才会犯同样的错误两次
Only a crazy man makes the same mistake twice.
我只是不明白你们这样的人 怎么会接受这样的工作
I don't understand why a man like you took the job in the first place. Hm? Why?
我也不知道了
I wonder myself.
来 告诉我为什么
No, come on. Come on, tell me why.
我在老家时认识一个男的 一天他脱下衣服跳进仙人掌中
A fella I knew in El Paso took all his clothes off and jumped on a cactus.
我也问他为什么
I asked him the same question: why?
结果呢？
And?
他说他当时觉得是个好主意
He said "It seemed to be a good idea at the time."
很好
Good!
是的
Right.
去拿你们的衣服 带上任何想要的东西
Go get your clothes, your saddlebags. Anything you want, take it.
就算你们的朋友欠你的
Your friends in there owe you at least that much.
桑德 去把马牵出来 苏洛 把枪拿走
Santos, pick up the carbines. Cirillo, the guns.
我第一次被雇做枪手
You know, the first time I took a job as a hired gun,...
就有人告诉我不能太关心客户
..a fella told me "Vin, you can't afford to care."
这就是你的致命伤
There's your problem.
我的问题不需要别人教我
One thing I don't need is somebody telling me my problem.
我说过 这就是你的问题
Like I said before, that's your problem.
从开始就对村子和村民 太关心了
You got involved in this village and the people in it.
你自说自话不会烦吗？
Do you ever get tired of hearing yourself talk?
我明白你的问题…
The reason I understand your problem so well...
是因为我也和你一样的陷进去了
..is that I walked into the same trap myself.
对
Yeah.
第一天来到这里 我就开始想
The first day we got here, I started thinking...
也许我可以放下手枪 安定下来 买块地…
..maybe I could put my gun away and settle down and get a little land,...
养一些牛
..raise some cattle.
他们虽然不太知道我 可是帮助他们对我只有好处
The things that these people know about me wouldn't work against me.
我… 只想让你知道 不是只有你上当的
I, uh... just didn't want you to think you were the only sucker in town.
我们可以和你一起走吗？罗那多
Can we go with you, Bernardo?
不行
No.
你喜欢我们 对不对？
You like us, don't you?
大概是吧
I guess so.
你是我们中间的一个 对吧？
You're one of us, aren't you?
对 我是你们中的一个
Yeah, I'm one of us all right.
带我们一起走吧 拜托
Take us with you! Please?!
不行
No!
我们没脸再住在这里了 我们的父亲们是… 软弱的人
We're ashamed to live here. Our fathers are... cowards.
不准说你们父亲是懦夫
Don't ever say that again about your fathers.
因为他们不是懦夫
They are not cowards!
你认为我勇敢是因为我戴着枪
You think I am brave because I carry a gun.
你们的父亲比我勇敢多了 因为他们有责任在肩…
Your fathers are much braver because they carry responsibility.
为了你 你的兄弟 姐妹和母亲
For you, your brothers, your sisters and your mothers.
而这种责任 有千斤重
This responsibility is like a big rock that weighs a ton.
责任压着他们直至埋进坟墓
It bends and it twists them until finally it buries them under the ground.
没有人说他们必须这么做
Nobody says they have to do it.
他们这么做是因为他们爱你 想为你们这么做
They do it because they love you and they want to.
我从来都没有这种勇气
I have never had this kind of courage.
打理一个农庄
Running a farm,...
每天像驴子一样的工作 却不一定有回报
..working like a mule, with no guarantee what will become of it -
这才是勇气
this is bravery.
这就是为什么我从不开始这种生活
That's why I never even started anything like that.
因此我从不这样
That's why I never will.
你们到边境另一边会更好
You'll do much better on the other side of the border.
你们在那儿可以偷牛 打劫火车
There you can steal cattle, hold up trains.
你只要担心被电死或被捉走
All you have to face is a sheriff, a marshal.
有次我抢了德州的一家银行
Once I rob a bank in Texas.
你们的政府派了一个军队来抓我 一队军人啊
Your government got after me with a whole army. A whole army!
只不过是家银行罢了 这意思很清楚
One little bank. It's clear, the meaning?
在德州 只有德州人才能抢银行
In Texas, only Texans can rob banks!
再见了
¡Adiós!
我早就可以告诉你 他们会出卖我们
I could have told you they'd sell us out.
农夫
Farmers...
Farmers!
没有尊敬 没有忠诚
No honor, no loyalty - nothin'.
他们唯一在意的就是那些宝贵的农作物和他们耕种的泥土
All they care about is their precious crops and the miserable dirt they dig in.
我恨他们
I hate 'em.
我恨他们所有人
I hate 'em all.
你当然恨
Sure you hate them.
因为你来自一个像这一样的农村
Because you come from a village just like that one.
你自己本身就是个农夫
You yourself are a farmer.
对
Yes.
对 我本是个农夫
Yes, I'm one of them.
但是谁把我变成这样的？
But who made us the way we are? Hm?
是那些带枪的人
Men with guns.
那些像卡贝拉的人…
Men like Calvera and...
和像你一样
..men like you.
像我一样的人
And now me.
你希望我们变成什么样呢？
So what d'you expect us to be?
没有任何人将我的枪抛来让我走 没有任何人
Nobody throws me my own guns and says run. Nobody.
我花了好久时间 才学会如何睡在石头上
It took me a long, long time to learn my elbow from a hot rock.
现在我属于那边境小镇 只想睡在白被单上
Right now, I belong back in that border town, sleepin' on white sheets.
我要回到那个村子去
I think I'll ride back to that village.
你们全都疯了 村民不会帮你们的 想想输的机率有多大
You're crazy, all of ya! They won't lift a finger to help. Think of the odds.
查理… 没有人叫你回去帮忙啊
Harry... nobody's asking you to go back.
走吧 没什么关系的
Ride on, Harry. It's all right.
我当然会走的
Bet your sweet life, I will!
走吧 李 如果他们想送死 让他们去吧
Come on, Lee. They wanna get killed? Let 'em.
跟他走 李 你没有欠任何人
Go ahead, Lee. You don't owe anything to anybody.
除了我自己以外
Except to myself.
你们都疯了 全部都疯了
You're crazy! All of ya!
走
Come on. Ya!
等等 克里斯 我会帮你们离开
Hold on, Chris, I'll get ya outta there!
克里斯…
Chris...
哈瑞？
Yes, Harry?
我不想死的这么窝囊
I'd hate to die a sucker.
我们不是为谷物和胡椒而来的
We didn't come here just to keep an eye on a lotta corn and chilli peppers.
这里真的有宝藏 对不对？
There was something else all the time, wasn't there?
是的 哈瑞 你一直是对的
Yes, Harry. You had it pegged right all along.
我就知道
I knew it.
是什么？
What was it?
黄金
Gold.
有很多很多
Sacks of it.
听起来真美
Oh... sounds beautiful!
大概值多少钱
How much?
至少有五十万
At least a half a million.
我的那份呢
My cut woulda been what?
大概七万元吧
About 70,000.
这真是太好了
I'll be damned!
也许你得不到
Maybe you won't be.
你们又回来了
You came back.
为了这样的一个地方
For a place like this.
为什么？
Why?
一群像你们这种人
A man like you?!
为什么？
Why?
罗那多 罗那多
Bernardo! Bernardo!
快回去 听到没？回去
No. No, get back. Go on! Get back.
我们不想这样
We didn't... We didn't mean to do it.
我们不是故意的
We didn't mean to do it.
看到没？
You see?
我说过 看你们的父亲
I told you. You see your fathers?
我叫什么名字？
What's my name?
罗那多
Bernardo.
Bernardo!
对
You're damn right.
你们可以留下来的 知道吗？
You could stay, you know.
他们会很高兴看你们留下来的
They wouldn't be sorry to have you stay.
也会很高兴看我们走的
They won't be sorry to see us go, either.
是的 仗已经打完了
Yes. The fighting is over.
你们的工作已经结束了
Your work is done.
对他们来说 每一季都有自己的任务
For them, each season has its tasks.
如果能有一季是专门为了感恩 他们对你们会更好的
If there were a season for gratitude, they'd show it more.
我们不会期望得到更多 老头
We didn't get any more than we expected, old man.
只有农夫们赢了
Only the farmers have won.
他们会永恒的留下来
They remain forever.
他们就像这片土地一样
They are like the land itself.
你们帮他们摆脱了卡贝拉…
You helped to rid them of Calvera,...
就像一阵强风 帮他们把蝗虫吹走了
..the way a strong wind helps rid them of locusts.
你们就像风一样…
You are like the wind,...
吹过了大地又走了
..blowing over the land and passing on.
谢谢你们 再见了
God be with you.
再见了
Adiós.
那个老头是对的
The old man was right.
只有农夫赢了
Only the farmers won.
我们输了
We lost.
我们总是输
We always lose.
剧终
谢谢观赏